- [Instructor] Okay, so now we'll actually
add the post endpoint
so we can add new items into your database.
So the first thing I'm going to do is start playing
in the playerControllers area.
So, you go into controllers. You open up that file here.
I'm going to close this for a second,
and I'm going to start doing a few things
such as importing mongoose from mongoose,
and then I'm going to import the player schema
that we've just completed in the previous video,
PlayerSchema from models/playerModel.
There you go.
Now we're going to create a player with the mongoose,
and again, IntelliSense trying to help me.
And then we're going to import the model,
pass the playerModel with the PlayerSchema.
So basically, what we're doing is telling the controller
that we're going to create, momentarily,
if you create a player,
it needs to be using this PlayerSchema.
So, if the values that we're passing to this schema
or the controller are not fitting to the PlayerSchema,
then it's going to throw us an error.
That's basically why we created the schema.
So now, we're going to create a function
to add a new player.
This is going to use our post endpoint
that we'll create in the routes after.
So we're going to use async,
so make sure that we have a response
before we actually resolve this particular function.
And we're going to let newPlayer use new Player.
So as you can see right now, we're going to leverage
this variable that we created with the request body.
We're going to pass the request body,
and say, well, check what we're passing here.
Does it have all the types that we've set
or the required types in certain case that we've set?
So we're going to try to save the newPlayer to the database
and get a response back in JSON
and pass whatever is the response, right?
If not, catch the error.
So, that is the typical way
that we're going to do this here.
So, if there's an error, please send it
so we can see what happens.
Okay, so now, we have our post controller.
Now, we need to create the route.
Otherwise, Express server can't execute the function
without having a route to actually execute that function.
So, let's go ahead and save this. Close this.
Let's go into our route here.
Close explorer and import on controller first,
so we're going to do it this way
'cause I'm going to have a bunch of controllers eventually.
And one quick method to see if you're importing
the right thing is always to do the from first.
That's a good practice if you want to make sure
that you're doing the right thing.
So controllers/playerControllers.
So again, you're getting out of that folder,
so dot, dot, getting into the controllers,
playerControllers and you're importing,
and now I'm going to do this and say add,
and as you can see, I have the export available
because of IntelliSense.
So, what I'm going to do is basically return this
on the second line 'cause I'm going to have
a bunch of controllers
that are going to be loaded here eventually.
So, I'm just going to do it like that.
And now, we're going to create the routes.
So, I'm going to create a variable called routes,
which will pass the app,
so that's basically the function
that we're using in the index here if you see it.
So, we're passing the routes function and passing the app,
so we can actually on comment here, save it,
'cause we're going to have to do this anyway.
So, right now the application,
if you have your Node application open,
it's going to break with what we just did
because we haven't defined this properly yet
and we haven't even exported it yet.
So, let's make sure we finish that code here
and we're going to create app.route
so whenever we hit that players end point,
we're going to post with the addNewPlayer controller,
and that's your post route, and that's pretty much it.
That's all we need.
So now, we need to export default routes
and we should be good to go.
So, I'm going to save this and then go into my terminal,
run New Terminal,
make sure that I haven't made any mistakes in my coding
'cause it's always good to check your work
'cause you may have done a typo somewhere,
not imported something properly.
Just check your work.
So, I'm going to cd backend, npm start,
and everything is running properly,
and now, we can actually go and check that route.
So, what I'm going to do is open Postman
and go to a post command,
and the URL is going to be localhost:4000/players.
Let me just make sure that my route is right.
Yeah, so players, plural.
And then in the body, you're going to make sure
you select form-urlencoded.
You're going to start putting the keys,
so what are the keys?
So if we go back to our schema.
Let's go back here, make sure we're doing the right things.
I'm going to minimize this here. Let's go to our route.
Close this.
What we need for sure is a first name, last name, email,
and everything else is not required,
so we can actually go without doing anything else.
So let's just, for the sake of testing,
let's go and do first name, last name, email for starters.
So, firstName, and you want to make sure you actually type it
the same way that it's written here in your schema.
So firstName, lastName, email.
So firstName, Manny,
lastName, Henry.
Email me@me.com for test purposes.
And then let's just add something else
just for the fun of it,
phone, and just add like (444) 555-1234.
And then what else? We could do ability.
Let's add two and let's go with that first.
So, this is the localhost:4000. Send that command.
And we have the response here.
So, we have basically a player created
firstName, Manny, blah, blah, blah, blah.
If you want to check it all the way down to the database,
you can go back to Studio 3T and do another search,
and as you can see, we have already a first player
that's been created in the database,
so the same thing, but the ID, Manny, Henry,
blah blah blah.
So, as you can see, it is fairly easy to add an endpoint
and then test it with Postman.
So, we can also get some very good tips on code syntax
when you come around to the front end piece.
So, what I mean by that is if you go back to Postman,
you can actually go here and click on Code
and get some code snippet
how to actually do a post command
to this particular API with specific code.
If you want to save time, you can actually do this.
You can switch to any type of languages.
So if you're working, for example, in Python,
you can see what the actual code will look like
if you make a post request to this particular URL.